In a groundbreaking new study, researchers discovered bottled water sold in stores can contain 10 to 100 times more bits of plastic than previously estimated — nanoplastics are so tiny that they cannot be seen under a microscope.
在一项开创性的新研究中，研究人员发现，商店出售的瓶装水所含的塑料颗粒可能比之前估计的多10到100倍——纳米塑料小到在显微镜下都看不见。
Nanoplastics are just 1/1000th the width of an average human hair — so tiny that experts say they can migrate through the tissues of the digestive tract or lungs into the bloodstream, distributing potentially harmful artificial chemicals throughout the body and into cells.
纳米塑料的宽度只有普通人头发的千分之一——小到专家说它们可以穿过消化道或肺部组织进入血液，把可能有害的人造化学物质散布到全身，并带入细胞。
One liter of water — equal to two standard-size bottled waters — contained an average of 240,000 plastic particles from seven types of plastics, of which 90% were identified as nanoplastics and the rest were microplastics, according to the new study.
根据这项新研究，一升水（相当于两瓶标准大小的瓶装水）平均含有来自七种塑料的24万个塑料颗粒，其中90%被确认为纳米塑料，其余是微塑料。
Microplastics are polymer fragments that can range from less than 0.2 inch (5 millimeters) down to 1/20000th of an inch (1 micrometer).
微塑料是聚合物碎片，大小从不到0.2英寸（5毫米）到1/20000英寸（1微米）不等。
Anything smaller is a nanoplastic that must be measured in billionths of a meter.
比这还小的就是纳米塑料，必须以十亿分之一米为单位来测量。
In the new study, published Monday in the journal Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, researchers from Columbia University presented a new technology that can see, count and analyze the chemical structure of nanoparticles in bottled water.
在周一发表于《美国国家科学院院刊》的这项新研究中，哥伦比亚大学的研究人员展示了一项新技术，能够观察、计数瓶装水中的纳米颗粒，并分析其化学结构。
Instead of 300 per liter, the team behind the latest study found the actual number of plastic bits in three popular brands of water sold in the United States to be in between 110,000 and 370,000, if not higher.
这项最新研究的团队发现，美国市场上三个热门品牌的瓶装水中，塑料颗粒的实际数量不是每升300个，而是在11万到37万之间，甚至更高。
“The innovative techniques presented in the study open the door for further research to better understand the potential risks to human health,” said Jane Houlihan, research director for Healthy Babies, Bright Futures — a nonprofit committed to reducing babies’ exposures to neurotoxic chemicals, who was not involved in the study.
“这项研究中提出的创新技术，为进一步研究打开了大门，有助于更好地了解人类健康面临的潜在风险，”非营利组织“健康婴儿，光明未来”的研究主任简·胡利汉说。该组织致力于减少婴儿对神经毒性化学物质的接触。胡利汉本人没有参与这项研究。
“Infants and young children may face the greatest risks, as their developing brains and bodies are often more vulnerable to impacts from toxic exposures,” said Houlihan in an email.
“婴儿和幼儿可能面临最大的风险，因为他们正在发育的大脑和身体往往更容易受到有毒物质暴露的影响，”胡利汉在一封电子邮件中说。
Nanoplastics are the most worrisome type of plastic pollution for human health, experts say.
专家表示，就人类健康而言，纳米塑料是最令人担忧的一类塑料污染。
That’s because the particles can invade individual cells and tissues in major organs, potentially interrupting cellular processes and depositing harmful chemicals such as bisphenols, phthalates, PFAS, and heavy metals.
这是因为这些颗粒能侵入主要器官中的单个细胞和组织，可能干扰细胞的正常运作，并沉积双酚类、邻苯二甲酸酯、全氟和多氟烷基物质以及重金属等有害化学物质。
There are things people can do to reduce their exposure to plastics, said Houlihan.
胡利汉说，人们可以采取一些措施减少对塑料的接触。
“We can avoid consuming foods and drinks in plastic containers.
“我们可以避免食用、饮用装在塑料容器里的食物和饮料。
We can wear clothing made from natural fabrics and buy consumer products made from natural materials,” Houlihan said.
我们可以穿天然面料制成的衣服，购买天然材料制成的消费品，”胡利汉说。
“We can simply assess the plastic in our daily lives and find alternatives whenever possible.”
“我们只需审视一下日常生活中的塑料，并尽可能地找到替代品。”